Guide to the J. D. McClatchy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
J. D. McClatchy papers
1900-2012
YCAL MSS 705
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
88.01
(108 boxes) + 1 art, 2 broadside folders
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, personal papers, printed material, audiovisual material, memorabilia, and artwork that document the life and work of author J. D. McClatchy from his youth to the 2010s. Correspondence is both personal and professional and includes letters from Anthony Hecht, James Merrill, Robert Penn Warren, and Richard Wilbur, among many other prominent figures of 20th and 21st century American literature, as well as correspondence relating to the publication of the Yale Review. Writings include drafts, proofs, and other material documenting the works of J. D. McClatchy, as well as journals and travel notebooks. Personal papers include documents, and diaries of Mary Jane McClatchy, mother of J. D. McClatchy.
McClatchy, J. D., 1945-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from J. D. McClatchy on the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, and the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 1994-2012; gift of J. D. McClatchy, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Audiovisual materials in boxes 57-59, 65, 67, 103, and 106: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 72, 76, 104 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
J. D. McClatchy (1945-)
J. D. McClatchy was born in Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, in 1945. He was educated at Georgetown and Yale, from which he received his Ph.D. in 1974. He has published several books of poetry, including Hazmat (2002) which was nominated for a Pulitzer Prize, and two collections of essays. He has also written text for several operas. McClatchy teaches in the English department at Yale University and serves as editor of the Yale Review.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, personal papers, printed material, audiovisual material, memorabilia, and artwork that document the life and work of author J. D. McClatchy from his youth to the 2010s. Correspondence is both personal and professional and includes letters from Anthony Hecht, James Merrill, Robert Penn Warren, and Richard Wilbur, among many other prominent figures of twentieth- and twenty-first-century American literature, as well as correspondence relating to the publication of the Yale Review. Writings include drafts, proofs, and other material documenting the works of J. D. McClatchy, as well as journals and travel notebooks. Personal papers include documents, and diaries of Mary Jane McClatchy, mother of J. D. McClatchy.
Arrangement
Organized into eight groupings: November 1994 Acquisition, October 1999 Acquisition, January 2000 Acquisition, August 2000 Acquisition, April 2001 Acquisition, October 2007 Acquisition, June 2012 Acquisition, and November 2012 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection was acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Yale Review; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Librettists -- 20th Century -- Archives; Critics -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital; Electronic documents; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Librettists -- United States -- 20th Century; Critics -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Hecht, Anthony, 1923-2004; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-; McClatchy, Mary Jane; Merrill, James, 1926-1995; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017; Yale University. Department of English
- November 1994 Acquisition, circa 1966-1993; 10.83; (11 boxes)
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 417
  Scope and Contents
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, audio tapes and printed material by or relating to J. D. McClatchy. Included are letters from Alfred Corn, Thom Gunn, Anthony Hecht, Daryl Hine, Robert Penn Warren, Richard Wilbur and others; writings of J. D. McClatchy, including drafts and other material relating to The Rest of the Way; writings of others; and personal papers, including school papers, juvenilia and memorabilia.
  Arrangement
  Organized into six groupings: Correspondence; Writings of Others; Writings of J. D. McClatchy; Printed Material; Mentions and Memorabilia of J .D. McClatchy; and Other Papers.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 106 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence
    Some files are arranged chronologically; other files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. This arrangement reflects the order in which the material was received.
    - General, 1981-1985; 11 (Box 1)
    - General, 1986-1989; 8 (Box 2)
      Audiocassette in Box 110: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - MCClatchy / B. Goldowsky, WPBX, Southampton, NY, 1988 July; 1; 00:26:20 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244252)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - General, 1989-1993; 9 (Box 3)
    - Ashbery, John, 1980-1986 (Box 4)
    - Berg, Steve, 1971-1980 (Box 4)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - Brodkey, H., 1977 (Box 4)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Brooks, Cleanth, 1968-1974 (Box 4)
    - Clampitt, Amy, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    - Corn, Alfred, 1976-1990 (Box 4)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Elmslie, Kenward, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
    - Erdrich, Dorris, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
    - Feldman, Irvine, 1980-1992 (Box 4)
    - Friar, Kimon, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1977-1981 (Box 4)
    - Glück, Louise, 1980-1987 (Box 4)
    - Gunn, Thom, 1981-1992 (Box 4)
    - Hacker, Marylin, 1986-1993 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Dan, 1985-1993; 2 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Donald, 1983-1991 (Box 4)
    - Hecht, Anthony, 1976-1994 (Box 4)
      Includes 1 audiocassette
      Audiocassettes in Box 4: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - L'Heureux, S. J., 1966-1971 (Box 4)
    - Heyen, William, 1971-1977; 2 (Box 4)
    - Hine, Daryl, 1976-1989 (Box 4)
    - Hollander, John, 1985-1993; 2 (Box 4)
    - John Hollander, Intro by J. D. McClatchy, Guggenheim Museum, 1989 October 19; 1; 01:27:01; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244278)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult access services for further information.
      Related Materials
      This audiocassette is related to material titled "Hollander, John, 1985-1993" found in Box 4, reference number 49.
    - Horgan, Paul, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
    - Howard, Richard, 1961-1994 (Box 5)
    - Hugo, Richard, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Kumin, Maxine, 1978-1985 (Box 5)
    - Lally, Michael, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Malone, Michael, 1986-1991 (Box 5)
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1985 (Box 5)
    - McCourt, James, 1980-1993 (Box 5)
    - Meredith, William, 1976-1983 (Box 5)
    - Merwin, W.S., 1976-1993 (Box 5)
    - Meyer, Thomas, 1978-1985; 2 (Box 5)
    - Monette, Paul, 1973-1987; 2 (Box 5)
    - Morgan, Fred, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - Moss, Howard, 1979-1986 (Box 5)
    - Oates, J. C., 1986-1994 (Box 5)
    - Pinsky, Robert, 1978-1991 (Box 5)
    - Reed, Jeremy, 1987-1991 (Box 5)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 1976-1989 (Box 5)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1988-1994; 3 (Box 5)
    - Salter, Mary Jo, 1979-1993 (Box 5)
    - Schuman, William, 1988-1990 (Box 5)
    - Schuyler, James, 1984-1990 (Box 5)
    - Shaw, R. B., 1982-1993 (Box 5)
    - Snodgrass, W. D., 1973-1993 (Box 5)
    - Sondheim, Stephen, 1990-1994 (Box 5)
    - Strand, Mark, 1975-1988 (Box 6)
    - van Duyn, Mona, 1974-1991 (Box 6)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1976-1990 (Box 6)
    - White, Edmund, 1979-1990 (Box 6)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1981-1991 (Box 6)
    - Williams, Charles, 1971-1980 (Box 6)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1977-1984 (Box 6)
    - Wright, Charles, 1976-1990 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1960-1990; 9 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1960-1990; 8 (Box 7)
  - Writings of Others
    - "Thermos" by Unidentified author, and "Redemption" by John Peck, 1980 (Box 7)
    - "Amphitryon", script translated by Richard Wilbur, undated (Box 7)
    - "Tom's Book of Sonnets", undated (Box 7)
    - "God's Creatures" and "The Rebirth of Venus", poems by Mary Jo Salter, 1986 (Box 7)
    - "The First Hour of Night" by Fred Bidart, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Untitled work, Chapter five, 1992 (Box 7)
    - The Gettysburg Review, 1989 (Box 7)
    - "Tongues on Trees" by Alfred Corn and John Gundelfinger, undated (Box 7)
  - Writings of J. D. McClatchy
    - "Rest of the Way", undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - "Question of Taste", undated (Box 7)
    - "After a Poet's Reading", 1990 May 29 (Box 7)
    - Washington Post, Book World and various printed materials, 1990 -1991 (Box 7)
    - "Stars Principal", undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - "White Paper", undated (Box 8)
    - "Vuelta", flyers, and correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
    - Hollander interview, undated (Box 8)
    - Charles Wright Interview, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Knopf catalogue, Rest of the Way, 1990 (Box 8)
    - "Rest of the Way", 1990 (Box 8)
    - Travels abroad notebook, undated (Box 8)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 8)
    - Hecht interview and incoming correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes, drafts, and correspondence, undated (Box 8)
    - Narrative/Descriptive in Kalston MS, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Unknown Essays, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - Southern Cross, undated (Box 8)
    - Orations and narratives, undated (Box 8)
    - Poetry, drafts, undated (Box 8)
    - Thomas Snapp correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - The New Republic, 1972 April 8 (Box 8)
    - Various drafts and notes, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 8)
    - Poems and short stories, undated; 5 (Box 9)
    - Yale faculty poets flyers, 1993 (Box 9)
    - "Blood Hot and Personal: Tradition of Contemporary Confession Poetry", undated (Box 9)
    - Poems for John Hollander, undated (Box 9)
    - "White Paper", undated (Box 9)
    - "My Mammogram", undated (Box 9)
    - Worksheet and choral composition, 1994 (Box 9)
    - "Rest of the Way", undated (Box 9)
    - "Love Alone" by Paul Monette, typescript, undated (Box 9)
    - "Stars Principal", typescript and dead matter, undated (Box 9)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 9)
  - Clippings and Memorabilia
    Includes clippings, literary journals, diplomas, varsity letter, and audiocassettes.
    - Clippings and Memorabilia, undated; 16; 16 folders (Box 10)
      Audiocassettes in Box 110: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Anne Sexton, 1973 July 3; 1; 01:49:49; A high background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244146)
    - Poetry Center, Marianne Moore, 1987 November 16; 1; 01:16:10 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244153)
    - J. D. McClatchy / WPBX, 1988 July 22; 1; 00:24:34 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244161)
    - Sexton: Radcliffe Institute, 1962 February 13; 1; 00:31:51; The program can only be heard on the right channel from about 20 seconds until 31:20. High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The program ends abruptly. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244179)
    - Anne Sexton, 1973 September 23; 1; 01:12:37; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244187)
    - Anne Sexton, 1973 July 3; 1; 00:31:07; The program ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. Left channel recorded slightly lower than the right one. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244195)
  - Other Papers
    - "A Question of Taste" (opera in one act), undated (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Yale poets flyer, 1991 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - The Hoya, 1966-1967; (2 volumes) (Box 11 (Oversize))
- October 1999 Acquisition, 1972-1995, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 632
  This portion of the collection consists of letters from James Ingram Merrill, with poems, photographs and printed material.
  - Letters from James Ingram Merrill, 1972-1995, undated; 20 (Box 12)
  - Manuscript items removed from printed material, 1982 (Box 12)
- January 2000 Acquisition, 1982-1993; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 650
  This portion of the collection consists of letters from James Ingram Merrill, Helen Plummer, David Jackson, Peter Hooten, and others; poems by James Merrill, and two audio tapes.
  Organized under two headings: Correspondence and Other Papers.
  - Correspondence
    Some files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. General files are arranged as a group at the end. This arrangement reflects the order in which the material was received.
    - Friar, Kimon, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Jackson, David, 1976-1985 (Box 13)
    - Hooten, Peter, 1985-1997 (Box 13)
    - Howard, Richard, July 2 (Box 13)
    - Plummer, Helen, 1982 (Box 13)
    - de Zogheb, Bernard, 1985-1993 (Box 13)
    - Yenser, Stephen, 1983, 1995 (Box 13)
    - General, 1972-1991; 20 (Box 13)
    - General, 1973-1994, undated; 5 (Box 14)
  - Other Papers
    - Miscellaneous Poems, undated (Box 14)
    - The Academy of American Poets, James Merrill: Education of the Poet, introduced by Rachel Hadas, Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1988 April 12; 1; 00:59:08; Static and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243809)
    - A Memorial Tribute to David Kalstone, New York Public Library, 1986 September 20; 1; 01:01:40 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243817)
      Included in the tribute: J. D. McClatchy, Richard Poirier, Maxine Groffsky, Edmund White, Alec Treuhaft, Charles Kalstone, Alfred Corn, and James Merrill.
- August 2000 Acquisition, 1992
  1 painting, framed, 87 x 79 cm
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 94
  This portion of the collection consists of a framed oil painting (Portrait of J. D. McClatchy).
  - Portrait of J. D. McClatchy, oil painting, 1992 (Box 105 (Art))
- April 2001 Acquisition, circa 1995-2000; 17.5; (19 boxes)
  Former call number Uncat MSS 140
  Organized under two headings: Correspondence and Other Papers
  This portion of the collection consists of general correspondence, Yale Review correspondence, drafts and other material relating to writings of J. D. McClatchy, printed material and other papers by or relating to J. D. McClatchy.
  Box 33: Restricted material. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1992-1995; 14 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1995-1998; 13 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1997-1999; 13 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1999; 4 (Box 18)
    - Personal correspondence, incoming, 1996-2000; 16 (Box 18)
    - Personal correspondence, incoming, 1996-1998; 6 (Box 19)
    - Personal correspondence and Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1996-2000; 13 (Box 19)
    - Personal correspondence and Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1997-1999; 4 (Box 20)
    - Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1992-2000; 14 (Box 20)
    - Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1992-2000; 20 (Box 21)
    - Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1998-2000; 16 (Box 22)
      Audiocassette in Box 22: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Yale Review correspondence, NY and company, J. D. McClatchy, 1998 May 6; 1; 00:20:09 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243791)
    - Yale Review correspondence, incoming, 1998; 4 (Box 23)
    - Academy of American Poets correspondence, incoming, 1998-2000; 16 (Box 23)
    - Academy of American Poets correspondence, incoming, 1996-1998; 4 (Box 24)
    - Academy of American Poets correspondence and business correspondence, incoming, 1973-2000; 25 (Box 24)
  - Other Papers
    - "Horace", undated (Box 25)
    - "Anthem", umdated (Box 25)
    - Untitled poem, undated (Box 25)
    - "Magnificat", undated (Box 25)
    - Musical scores, undated (Box 25)
    - Published works, 1970-1974 (Box 25)
    - Chapter XI, undated (Box 25)
    - "Setting the Other Free" New Yorker, 1995; 2 (Box 25)
    - "Two Deaths, Two Lives", 2000; 2 (Box 25)
    - James Merrill, undated (Box 25)
    - "My Fountain Pen", undated (Box 25)
    - Bound writings, undated (Box 25)
    - Introduction to the Magic Flute, undated (Box 25)
    - Address book and notepad, undated (Box 25)
    - Calendar, 1986 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous notes and poems, undated (Box 25)
    - "Glanum", undated (Box 25)
    - "Fado", undated (Box 25)
    - "Two Deaths, Two Lives", undated (Box 25)
    - "Ouija", undated (Box 25)
    - "Penis", undated (Box 25)
    - Essay- James Dickey, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Essay- Longfellow, undated (Box 25)
    - "Voice of a Poet", undated; 3 (Box 25)
    - "Glanum", undated (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous poems, undated; 3 (Box 25)
    - Poems and correspondence, undated (Box 25)
    - "Ode", undated (Box 25)
    - Notes and drafts of poems, autograph, undated (Box 25)
    - Drafts of "My Early Hearts", undated (Box 25)
    - "Ten Commandments", undated (Box 25)
    - The W. H. Auden Society Newsletter, 1999 November (Box 25)
    - "Ten Commandments", undated (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous poems and notes, undated (Box 25)
    - "My Early Hearts", 1996 June 17 (Box 25)
    - Translation of "The Magic Flute", 1999-2000 (Box 25)
    - "Lexington Avenue Subway, 1941", undated (Box 25)
    - Poem for John Peradotto, undated (Box 25)
    - "Elbows", undated (Box 25)
    - "Two Deaths", 1999 (Box 25)
    - "The Voice of the Poet" and birthday poems for Richard Wilbur, undated (Box 26)
    - "Ten Commandments", undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - "The Folding Cliffs" by W.S. Merwin, 1997 (Box 26)
    - "Twenty Questions", undated (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 26)
    - Notebooks, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - James Merrill, undated (Box 26)
    - Calendars, 1984-1995; 8 (Box 26)
    - Calendars, 1990-1999; 4 (Box 27)
    - The American Academy of Arts and Letters annual ceremonial invitation, 1999 (Box 27)
    - "Just Let Me Say This About That", 1997 (Box 27)
    - Biographical piece, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 27)
    - "The Dialogue of Desire and Guilt", undated (Box 27)
    - Printed ephemera, undated (Box 27)
    - "What They Left Behind", undated (Box 27)
    - "William Schuman: A Reminiscence", undated (Box 27)
    - Review of "Flight Among the Tombs" by Anthony Hecht, undated (Box 27)
    - Essay on Robert Penn Warren, undated (Box 27)
    - "A Birthday Poem for Chip", 1997 (Box 27)
    - "On Thorton Wilder", undated (Box 27)
    - "Tattoos", undated (Box 27)
    - "Ten Commandments", 1997 (Box 27)
    - "Aden", undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled poems, 1997; 2 (Box 27)
    - Notes, undated (Box 27)
    - "Fado", undated (Box 27)
    - "Cloudstar", undated (Box 27)
    - Untitled poems, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - "Ouija", undated (Box 27)
    - Interview, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 27)
    - Tribute to James Merril, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous essays and letters, undated (Box 27)
    - Introduction to "A Tribute to W. H. Auden", 1991 (Box 27)
    - "A Picture of Us", undated (Box 27)
    - "Ouija", undated (Box 27)
    - "Under Hydra", undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous reviews and notes, undated (Box 27)
    - "The Voice of the Poet", undated (Box 27)
    - Notebooks, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous poems, correspondence, and notes, undated (Box 27)
    - WNYC contract, 1994 (Box 27)
    - James Merrill, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 27)
    - "Tea with the Local Saint", undated (Box 27)
    - "Betrayal", undated (Box 27)
    - "Proust in Bed", undated (Box 27)
    - "In the Spirit", undated (Box 27)
    - "Mario and the Magician", 1990 (Box 27)
    - "Anatomies of Melancholy", undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous poems and notes, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - Speech, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, clippings, and correspondence, undated; 18 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, clippings, and correspondence, undated; 14 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, clippings, and correspondence, undated; 23 (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, clippings, and correspondence, undated; 15 (Box 31)
    - Poster for Borders, undated (Box 32 (oversize))
    - Essays, undated (Box 33)
- October 2007 Acquisition, 1987-2006; 36; (40 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 984
  Box 72: Restricted fragile material. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence; printed material, including magazines, newspapers and other printed material containing references to J. D. McClatchy; writings; financial papers, personal papers; computer disks; and other papers.
  Organized under five headings: Correspondence; Mentions of J. D. McClatchy; Opera; Poetry, Book Projects, and Other Writings; and Other Papers.
  - Correspondence
    Arranged chronologically, based on the order in which the material was received.
    - General, 2001; 35 (Box 34)
    - General, 2001; 31 (Box 35)
    - General, 2001; 24 (Box 36)
    - General, 2002; 49 (Box 37)
    - General, 2002; 41 (Box 38)
    - General, 2003; 14 (Box 39)
    - General, 2003-2004; 16 (Box 40)
      Audiocassette in Box 40: Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - General, 2004; 15 (Box 41)
    - General, 2005; 19 (Box 42)
    - General, 2005-2006; 21 (Box 43)
    - General, 2006; 24 (Box 44)
    - Allan Gurganus reading, "He's at the Office", from "Best American Stories, 2000", 2000 December; 1; 01:27:19; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091243825)
      A message on the audiocassette reads: Dear Chip and Sandy. Love at Christmas 2000, Allan.
  - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2001
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 28 (Box 45)
      Includes 1 compact disc
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2001-2002; 26 (Box 46)
    - Recorded, undated; 1; 00:55:04; A high amount of background noise and static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244211)
      An operatic performance can be heard on the tape.
    - Rachel Hadas, WNYC, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244229)
    - McClatchy on Millay, 2002 January 17; 1; 01:01:44; The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244237)
    - NY and Company, 2001 April 10; 1; 00:18:24 (Box 106, Item barcode 39002091244245)
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2003; 37 (Box 47)
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2003-2004; 28 (Box 48)
    - Mentions of J. D. McClatchy, 2004-2005; 30 (Box 49)